Okay , calm , come on .
Calm down
Who wants to see ghosts ?
Who wants to see some ghosts ?
Ghosts !
Okay , that 's better .
First , hello , welcome .
My name is David Williams , this is my colleague , Clare McManus .
We archivists at the National Film Archive .
Today will see a series of films , dating from 1895 to 1905 .
It is worth to note to all who see ...
in these films , are long dead . ..
All these people , men , women and children ...
have disappeared from the face of the earth forever .
So , in a sense , is and see real ghosts .
Well , well !
Let 's watch it and see what you think .
Thanks .
Do not worry ... She 'll love .
Hello !
- Hey ... I 'm glad to see you ! How are you ? - I 'm glad to see you .
This is my wife Alice .
- Hello ! - Hello ! Great meeting you !
Nice to meet you finally . I 'm sorry I ...
I have come last . Was ... Busy ...
No , no , no , no ... Not at all !
So ... I 'm going to let them in , look for themselves .
I 'll be here waiting for you , take all the time they need .
Okay , thank you .
Come on then !
Come ; Your first .
Are you coming ?
No . I 'm too nervous .
You go , turn around .
- Love it ! - You Sure .
five years later
Alice ...
have a message .
Have a message
Who is it ?
Mom ...
Dad .
Hi honey ...
heard a noise and woke and now I have to go to the bathroom .
I will .
Pa ' ... Are you afraid of the dark ?
No . Of course not .
Why , do you ?
No , but it could be something hidden in the dark .
What ?
Monster .
Good night . OK . I love you .
Good night dad , I love you .
Want to tell me dinosaurs who can name ?
Maybe tomorrow .
Can you say goodnight to Mickey and dragon heads ?
Good night !
Is he well ?
Yeah , okay .
Who was the message ?
Steve .
At work .
Just because you do not have a life , thinks all ...
others should be available 24 hours to be called .
Sorry . I should have turned off before .
I love you .
Good night .
What time do you start work ?
What is this ?
- What is this ? - Not until 10 .
Okay , come on .
Have a nice day , dear .
Goodbye , I love you .
Goodbye . I love you too .
Thanks .
Come on .
Bye guys !
Bye Mommy !
Alosauro , Brontosaurus , T-Rex , Triceratops , Stegosaurus , that 's the best !
Go ! God , you 're getting so ...
intelligent , that 's more than I can name !
Do you think you would be able to swim there ?
It can not be ... No ... is too deep .
Would you be able to swim there ?
No ...
No , it 's too deep for me too .
Billy ... Billy ...
Billy ! Billy !
Hey , do not go there , I told you .
A girl in our school saw a ghost there .
Well , I know nothing about ghosts , but could have rats there .
's Dirty .
Can I throw a stone and see if a ghost comes ?
Want to throw a stone ?
Okay , just one .
Then we must go .
Do you have one ?
Okay ?
Can I throw another ?
No ! Come , we 'll be late .
According .
'll Pick you up later .
Goodbye Dad !
Have a nice day .
hope you feel better than you look
I did not sleep much last night .
No ?
Why , I feel so bad ?
No worse than usual !
Anyway , I probably I do not look much better !
I was up until 4 a. m . Displaying Cat People and the Curse of the ...
Cat People ? Does passed ? I love that movie !
Yes ... I was going to speak , but ... I figured you needed your beauty sleep !
Yes ... Very funny .
Listen , do not want to take to lose day job
but some movies came to the file ;
Some from the file police , could be interesting .
Yes
- Do revisarías for me ? - Claro .
Great . Thank You .
CRIME SCENE 1902
Hey ... That 's my way .
I had a very strange day today .
Saw a film of 1902 , our house was in it .
There was a murder here . A man ...
killed his wife . It happened in this room .
What ?
I would not worry about that . Horrible things happen in every old house .
Only these dinosaurs govern their ...
Williams Looks amazing lady !
Oh ! Thank you , Sophie !
This is my husband , David .
- Hello ! - Hi .
Sophie used to be the nanny of Thompson , two doors down .
Mom , Sophie has not even heard of Stegosaurus .
Well , not everyone knows about dinosaurs , you know !
Okay , make yourself at home , and sírvete any food in the kitchen .
We should get home too late .
Tomorrow . OK ?
Sleep well .
Nice to meet you .
Alice !
Hello !
Alex is here . Come on .
'm Sure you remember to David , my husband .
Hello .
You , uh , Librarian ?
The ... Archivist .
Glad to see you again .
Also .
I 'm sure you will not mind if I borrow your lovely wife
for a few moments , that someone ...
I would really like to know .
No , not at all ! I 'll get a drink .
Yes , I 'm fine .
Can I help you , sir ?
Hey can I have another ... ?
Another gin and tonic ?
Hello .
Sorry for that .
What was that all about ?
Things work .
He wanted me to meet this customer , but I did not .
Not tonight .
I thought he was the client .
Yes ...
he is .
But he wanted me to meet another .
A colleague .
Come . Let 's dance .
I 'll just finish this .
I love you .
Sorry ! I could not resist .
Are you okay ?
- Yes - You look pale ..
No , I 'm fine .
Yes ?
More paler than usual , even .
I have the last 7 or 8 of those movies donated ,
aligned in the room projection , you 'd miss out ?
Yes , of course .
TERRIBLE CRIME DIC . 12 , 1902
♪ Twinkle , twinkle , little star , how I wonder what you ♪
♪ On top of the world so high , like a diamond the sky ... ♪
♪ Twinkle , Twinkle , Little Star ♪
Kiss !
Goodbye child .
Goodbye mom .
Wait till your dad , Billy !
Hey , do not work late tonight .
- Come straight home . - Why ?
What ?
It will not be too late , I promise .
Goodbye .
Alice !
Hello ?
Dad ! I 'm still in school , will you come for me
Dad , did you forget me ?
I just lost track of time .
Sorry .
Adam and I were the only ones left .
Adam said a Gowilla could beat one Winosaurus in a fight , is it true ?
No .
The master wants you
David ...
want you to listen ...
forgive me ... No , God ...
I do not want ...
David please ...
Please ... No , no ...
do not
I do not want to die
Hi , I 'm Alice here , so sorry if I I missed your call
If you want to leave your name and number I 'll be in ...
contact you as soon as I possible . Thank you
Detective McNamara .
So , when I saw him last ?
Eh ... Yesterday morning .
We said goodbye , do Billy , my son , to school .
And she has been out all night before ?
No .
No , never .
Said he 'd be working until late last night , but I asked a ...
coworker of Hersand and said ...
Alice was about five .
Did you have an argument ?
No .
Are you sure ?
Yes
Have you been in touch with family and friends ?
And have not heard of it ?
No .
Okay ...
Hair Color ?
Some of them are a bit old .
That 's all I could find .
Dad ...
returns when mommy ?
I told you ... will be in home soon . Do not worry .
Pretty ...
- Hello . - Hi .
Is there any news ?
How is Billy ?
Yeah , okay .
I got to bed an hour ago .
He wanted to sleep in her room .
You know there 's something black in his hands ?
They took my fingerprints digital to eliminate me .
In case there is an inquiry .
Eh ... I stuck Billy in bed an hour ago .
He wanted to sleep in her room .
He 's fine . All day . We get along great !
He 's a great guy , I really sympathize .
Get to know everything about dinosaurs !
I know , yes !
Me I better go .
Yes
Thanks .
See you in the morning .
Si .
Billy ... Billy ! What are you looking at ?
Come here ...
I had a dream about Mommy .
I miss .
A man came yesterday saying be the lover of his wife .
Says was with her the night she disappeared .
They have been going out together for a year .
Do you know anything about that ?
No .
Well , according to him , was planning to leave .
That 's impossible .
She loves me .
Has a lover , David .
He 's lying !
Well , several of its friends have supported him .
In what counts , was love with the guy , and he with her .
Sorry .
Cursed acid reflux .
Total fucking pain in the ass .
Want one of these ?
No .
I have a very weak stomach , David .
Not kill her , right ?
No right to be wondering these things .
I love , love my wife .
Never I never do anything to hurt her .
Never .
Le asking your lover these questions , right ?
Yes
Do you ask him if he killed her ?
He has an alibi .
Your boss called right as he left his house ,
listened both insisting on going home alone ...
and then the phone went on for ...
Over an hour , so that is solid , man !
People always suspect the husband .
Do you know why that is ?
Because it 's always the husband .
Every damn time .
Is this your wife ?
Is this your wife , Alice Williams ?
Yes
Yes , it 's my wife .
There was no evidence of foul play or assault .
Drowned .
Must have been dropped .
Was it an accident ?
Yes
Think so .
One of the heel of his shoe party it would ,
That we think could have caused his downfall .
So , the absence of any evidence to the contrary ,
we have to conclude that it was an accident yes .
Do you agree ?
Did you know she was pregnant ?
Therefore entrust your body to the ground
Earth to earth
Ashes to Ashes / i .
Dust to Dust
Sorry for your loss .
Thanks .
Nana .
She loved you .
You knew , right ?
Yes ?
She loved you .
More than any other thing in the world .
Yes
Oh Billy !
Billy .
Come , go with Clare , okay ?
How are you ?
Yeah , okay .
Children are strong .
They are stronger than most adults even .
Of course , they do not really understand , right ?
Maybe I should take him for a while .
It might be good for him .
I think Alice would have liked that .
He should be around another woman .
A mother figure .
Sophie living with us now ...
The nanny Billy ...
I think it 's best if stays home with me .
Did you hear about Alex ?
Alex ?
Alice 's boyfriend .
Apparently , he has taken Alice 's death very badly .
He is completely devastated .
Say he had to go to a hospital .
To recover .
Yes
I give a shit .
Do you understand me ?
No I could care less , I have my son .
Many people loved her .
I loved her .
I have to go .
I only say goodbye to Billy .
Been a long day .
Are you okay ?
Lied .
I , uh , I lied to the police .
I know this Alex guy .
Actually does not matter now anyway , right ?
Was an accident .
The thing is ...
on the night she disappeared .
I went to his house ,
like that , and went after them ...
and saw them in bed together .
I did nothing .
Know , I could have done , but I did not . I just went .
Not even see me .
On the way home I felt ...
so sick just had to go to the public baths ...
canal side and vomited everywhere ,
and remember , I was feeling sick , and I looked up ,
and someone looking over the cubicle wall to me .
Was a man .
I managed to get to the door , and just before I passed out .
Swear I saw him with his hands around her throat ,
and he was , he was trying to kill .
He was killing her , and could not move , could do nothing .
And then when he did not return home the next day ...
I mean , I 've seen was real ... Clare ...
was very real .
So you have to tell the police .
Tell them that what I said , do not even know ,
not even know how the guy looked .
No matter , tell them anyway ...
Once you tell them followed Alice into that house , that would be it .
Okay ?
They , they just , they just thought it was me .
What are you going to do ?
I have to find him first .
As I have that .
KILLS WIFE HUSBAND WIFE INFIEL stabbed 52 TIMES WITH KITCHEN KNIFE
MURDERER 'S WIFE ESCAPA , NANA KILLER , THEN DROWNING CHILDREN AND HERSELF , IN CHANNEL
WOMAN BODY FOUND IN THE CANAL
then beheaded nanny , with an ax ...
had the opportunity to see old camera ...
David
What ?
The old camera .
Eh , no , sorry . What I do now .
Okay . Do it in the morning .
What is this ?
It 's just ...
Hey , just ...
unsolved crimes .
The killings that occurred in the city around the canal .
I found online .
Just reviewed it .
Let 's see if I can find similarities .
David .
You must take time to mourn , not think about things like this .
I 'll find something .
Yes , only I have to keep looking , that 's all .
So what are you going to get ?
- A puppy . - A puppy
Do you know which receive
So it would not be a surprise
Dad , look what ? . we did !
Go ! It 's great !
I hope you do not mind . I know how busy you are .
No , of course not .
I had completely forgotten .
Daddy , pick me up , so I put the angel on top .
Want put the angel on top , right ?
To mere above .
Okay , here we go . Are you ready ?
When you want ...
1-2-3 ... Come , stretch !
David , not
Sorry to bother you .
Was thinking we could make a real ...
effort with decorations and stuff this year .
I think it would be good for Billy .
What do you think ? I could buy more lights for the stars .
And yes , I thought I could decorate all the other rooms and stuff ...
do , like , very Christmassy .
Yes
Yes That sounds a good idea ..
Okay ?
Yes , I 'm fine .
YOUNG MOTHER KILLS BABY IN ARSON
Mr. Williams .
Goodnight Sophie .
Want us to move ?
Is not good , stay where you are .
Hello ...
anybody there ?
Sophie ?
Sorry !
Sorry .
Look , can you come to my room for a second ?
Why ?
Hey , just for a second .
Do not ... Listen ! He is very weak .
- What would that be ? - Just listen .
Do you hear ?
I can not hear anything .
No , he stopped .
There 's something behind there .
Maybe it 's just a rat .
No , no . It 's not a rat .
I can not hear anything .
What can you hear ?
Is someone whispering as if in prayer .
Maybe it 's just the house next door .
I do not know ...
no , no , no , the walls are very solid .
Dad , what are you doing ? He slept .
Billy ...
Billy , go to bed .
Okay .
's Nothing . All is well .
Take him to bed , you do .
Come . We have to go to bed .
I want to stay .
What does Dad ?
What ?
Billy , go to your room , get dressed .
You and Sophie will go from here .
I 'll just wrap the belt .
That is .
Okay , I 'll see you tomorrow .
I love you .
I 'm not sure about this .
Sophie , sorry for this .
You 're just going to have to trust me . OK ?
It 's not safe here , is not safe for you and Billy .
Everything is paid at the hotel , they are waiting .
Okay .
Can ask all you want room service .
'll See you tomorrow . Thank You .
Yes
Come on ... Come on ...
Okay , just happens ...
Okay , there ... There , you see ?
Yes ...
I see . Is anyone there .
Okay , there 's more ...
Just wait ...
And there ... There ...
Did you see its outline ?
Hard to say , could be just a shadow .
Oh come on , there 's someone there .
Maybe . It 's really hard to say .
Tell me what you think about this ?
Believe what ?
This is the man who killed Alice .
This is the same man who saw on the night he was killed .
What do you mean ?
I think there are ghosts in my house .
David ... !
I know this sounds crazy , believe me , I know how fucking crazy this sounds ,
but I 've seen things , I hear things , is the only rational explanation .
- I do not think so ! - Yes it is !
Okay , okay , wait until you hear this .
In the 1930s seances were carried out at home ,
people said they saw a shadow , a shadow .
Is it a coincidence , that 's all .
The previous owner , way , the Realtor ...
said it was an old woman who was senile ,
but was not .
We lied .
Was a young woman who tried burn his house while his family slept .
Now his son died in the fire , but swore that he did not .
Like me with Alice .
Said it was the devil .
Said a man who could not see , tried to rape her .
Said he was a demon living behind walls .
The walls , Clare .
Stop for a moment . Stop for a moment .
Could you think what you 're saying ?
Think I 'm having a nervous breakdown is not it ?
Well , maybe I have .
No .
- Well , maybe ... - Only these exhausted .
- Right ? . - Yes
Billy ?
Sophie ?
Billy can you hear me ?
Dad , why do not you come to see us today
Sorry .
Wanted , simply I did not feel very well .
Can you come and see us tomorrow
Yes Yes , I promise .
What have you eaten ?
We ate burgers , fries , ice cream and Coca-Cola for dinner .
Go ...
My belly is big , look how fat I 'm Dad
Sophie Billy does this again in the room with you ?
No , still in the shower .
Billy , I want you to move the laptop around , okay ?
Just move the laptop around for can see the rest of the room , dale .
Please ?
Keep moving ...
keeps moving the laptop .
That 's it . Good boy . Keep moving a little more ...
that 's all ...
just had to see ...
room .
What is that ?
Billy ...
Billy ! Billy , leave the room !
Billy !
Sorry , sorry .
How did you get here so fast ?
Mr. Williams ?
I 'm not sure if I work here anymore .
I do not know what is happening .
Y ...
if it were not for Billy , think I would go now .
Understand .
Yes , you 're right , you gotta go .
I can not guarantee your safety and and ...
is not sure 're around .
I do not want to leave behind Billy ...
but really do not think it 's right , Mr. Williams .
Maybe if you tell me what was happening , would understand or could help .
Please Sophie , have to leave tomorrow .
Best sleeps here with us tonight .
'll Take the floor , can stay in bed .
No , okay . I 'll be fine .
No . No , no , please .
You will not .
Mr. Williams , I want to talk to you about this again in the morning .
About me bringing me , I mean .
Yes
Good night .
- Come ... - No .
Let me go !
Come ...
No ...
- No ! - Please .
Come on , get out .
No ... What are you doing ! ?
Just downstairs ...
Let me out
Mr. ! Williams
Where is dad , who is in the house ?
Do not know ...
No .
Mr. Williams , let me out .
Let us leave ...
Billy afraid ...
've checked everywhere .
Dad !
Me and Billy ...
were following someone out ...
Okay , then I heard her scream .
're Trying to separate .
Did you see anyone up there ?
Did you ?
Let Billy !
No , no ...
Billy will stay with me .
Sophie ... !
Hey Billy ...
Have you seen other people in the house ?
Billy ...
if you see someone , you know you have to say ?
Right ?
Are you sure ?
Where is Sophie
DEEP WATER HAZARD STAY AWAY - She left this morning
DEEP WATER HAZARD STAY AWAY . . - She will not back
Billy ... You see that woman ?
Where ?
There ...
's See , he 's hiding in the grass ?
I can not see anyone .
Are we going to see my teacher today ?
No . Not today .
Billy ... Billy returns .
- Go . Back ... - What ?
Go ... Go hide behind the wall .
Come on ...
Turn ... Turn , count to 10 .
Okay ?
One ...
two ... Forward ...
1 ...
2 ...
4 ...
10 ... !
Is this a game of hide and seek , can I open my eyes now ?
Clare ...
David ...
Are you okay ?
- Hey , Billy ! - Hello !
- I need to disclose this . - What is it ?
's Nothing .
Just let me reveal , did not take long .
You need to tell me what is first .
Please Clare , do not make me beg .
Really have to see this .
- Please . - OK .
But it will be a couple of days though .
No . No , I have to see him today ...
Well ... I need him now .
Is completely full here .
Come on .
Well , I 'll get it done , I promise .
I 'll bring Even when is done , right ?
Look ...
I 've been thinking ...
Maybe you should talk to someone ?
Know , maybe ...
A grief counselor or something .
Just ...
think about it , okay ?
I will .
If someone walk here this evening , will see their footprints .
It Snow !
Can I continue ?
Yes !
Now no one can enter without us knowing .
You like me
What about all the dust , Dave ?
Meal is cooking .
Do not tell me ?
What about all the flour , 're making a cake ?
What do you want ?
Dress .
You come with me .
Found a hammer in the channel , with your fingerprints on it .
A hammer that belonged to loving your wife .
He says he was lost , the night she disappeared .
Can you explain that ?
There was a murder in my house ...
in 1902 .
What ... ?
You can check all this ; And a man killed his entire family .
You understand me ...
and I think he was the one who did it .
I have evidence , I caught something on film .
's A ghost .
We will see in a few days .
As welfare official senior , I have ...
choice but to recommend appropriate to Services ...
Social and recommend that the child is taken care .
Is not that a little harsh ?
Mr. Williams has just lost his wife .
Its symptoms are clearly part of a process of mourning .
Enclose nannies in closets and hearing voices ... ?
Behind walls , is part of the grieving process ?
It was just a nanny and people react ...
differently to the death of a loved one ...
and , incidentally , is the same nanny Mr. . Williams ...
caught smoking drugs in his room , so ...
No way !
Yes
Yes , we can do that .
Wait to return psychiatrist 's report ...
and then we 'll see what do after that .
I will not go to a psychiatrist .
There 's nothing wrong with me .
You have to . We agreed on that .
What you were . I do not .
I will not go .
I have to go back to Billy .
Dad ...
Who are these men ?
Are the police .
Do not look .
Is there anybody out ?
No .
Dad ...
What ?
Never leave me , right ?
No . Of course not .
What if you die as Mommy , what would become of me then ?
Never leave you , Billy .
Never .
And always be together , you and me .
Okay ?
Now , close your eyes .
REVENGE VIL
- Did you see it ? - No .
Would you ... ?
Do you want to see me ?
I 'm afraid to look for myself .
Okay .
Go watch TV , go ...
David ... Do you remember call me last night ?
Last night ? No .
You did .
You were delirious , I hardly recognized your voice .
You were crying .
You said you wanted to tell me something about Alice .
That was not me . I have not called .
Ven . Sit .
If you hurt , if did , maybe you should ...
done with it ... I go to the police .
'll Go with you , if want it to .
I 'll tell you how good a person you are .
I 'll help .
Clare , sacrificed children in this room ...
do not you know ?
David what are you talking about ?
The blood of a baby is more powerful , do you see ?
They dragged the bodies through here ...
sewers and dumped in the canal .
In the canal !
They ... They thought of everything ...
David , stop , stop !
Just ... Look at me !
You killed Alice ?
Just say did not ... Look into my eyes .
Say you did not .
Say you did not , please !
Just tell me !
Whatever you say , I think .
Whatever you say , whatever you say thing , I believe you .
'll Believe you ...
I 'll believe you ...
Just tell me ...
just tell me ...
Just look at this .
Then you 'll understand .
Yes , we ... We will see this .
Okay , there it is ... Do not you see ?
Moves ...
Do you see ?
David ...
nothing there .
Just wait , wait ... there 's more .
Okay ... there ... there !
You see ? , there , look !
What is it there ?
Moves to us , do not you see ?
What is it ?
- Yes ... I see something ... - See it ?
I see something .
I told you I 'm telling the truth ...
What is it ?
No I 'm going crazy !
You understand me ...
look there !
What is it ?
David ...
David , turn it off !
Turn it off , what is it ?
David what is it ?
David , please turn it off !
Nooo !
To !
What happens then ?
Not me .
We saw him enter the house with a woman ,
- then we heard her screams . - What have you done , David ?
What have you done ?
I did not !
Open the door , David
Mr. Williams ...
David ! Open the door !
Open the damn door , David
Arriba !
David
Back !
David !
To !
Stop , stop ... To ...
Look at me ...
True , there 's .
There ! It moves
David ...
no , there 's nothing there ...
No ... It is moving towards us ...
Do you see
Watch
I want you to see .
- You can see it ! ! - Not there is nothing
Go out there !
The master wants
Give it
- I could not help ... - You a fucking whore / .. ! i
David , I love you
You 're a fucking bitch ! That 's what you 're
I did not mean for this to happen
I have to go , I have to take Billy me . ..
No , no , David , sorry ...
- Thou shalt not take Billy ! - No , no ...
Fucking bitch
David ...
No , David
Da ...
David ! Help
Help ! David
David
Alice ...
David ...
Are you okay ?
When will the first review , then ?
The next Monday .
- Does that give you enough time ? - Oh , yeah ,
the house will be empty next Fridays . I do not want to waste time .
I just want the serious people see this house .
Course . I feel the same .
Nana , ¿ I can come and bring my book dinosaur ?
Yeah , yeah ... Do not delay , because we are now going .
I have a list of appointments and in a row next week .
Billy ...
Billy , here
Is papi ...
I 'm here with your mother
We miss you
IS SOLD
You want to stay here us ?
You want to stay with us forever
I love Billy
I love you .
Billy !
A translation of TaMaBin
fix Eurogroup _ sub